<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<aiml version="2.0">
    
    
<category>
    <pattern>hello</pattern>
    <template>
        Hello, I&apos;m a chatbot here to help you explore future career choices in computer science and software development! Enter your name in the form "My name is [name]" and let&apos;s get started.
    </template>
</category>

<category>
    <pattern>hello *</pattern>
    <template>
        Hello, I&apos;m a chatbot here to help you explore future career choices in computer science and software development! Enter your name in the form "My name is [name]" and let&apos;s get started.
    </template>
</category>

<category>
    <pattern>My name is *</pattern>
    <template>
        <think>
            <set name = "student_name"><star/></set>
        </think>
        Nice to meet you, <get name = "student_name"></get>. Are you here for career advice today?
    <reply>
        Yes, please assist me
    </reply>
    <reply>
        No, I&apos;m looking for something else
    </reply>
    </template>
</category>

<category>
    <pattern>Yes, please assist me</pattern>
    <template>
        I&apos;ll ask you a few basic questions about your studies and interests. Are you currently studying computer science or a related field?
    <button>
        I&apos;m studying in a computer science field
    </button>
    <button>
        I&apos;m in another degree program
    </button>
    </template>
</category>

<category>
    <pattern>_ studying in a computer science field</pattern>
    <template>
        Do you prefer programming or high-level design?
    <reply>
        Programming
    </reply>
    <reply>
        Designing
    </reply>
    </template>
</category>

<category>
    <pattern>Designing</pattern>
    <template>
        Do you prefer working on websites and user experience or the architecture of systems and processes?
    <button>
        Websites and user experience
    </button>
    <button>
        System and process architecture
    </button>
    </template>
</category>

<category>
    <pattern>Websites and user experience</pattern>
    <template>
        You may be interested in careers in frontend development and UX/UI design. Frontend development creates the user-facing elements of an application, such as the webpage itself. These developers frequently work with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and frameworks such as Angular.
        They work to make the user experience as clear, convenient, and efficient as possible.
        UX/UI design is tasked with creating intuitive user interfaces and experiences. This involves a number of considerations such as the layout, icons, colors, and how elements interact, as well as making modifications to meet users' needs and expectations.
    </template>
</category>

<category>
    <pattern>System and process architecture</pattern>
    <template>
        You may be interested in a career in development and operations, frequently referred to by DevOps. DevOps engineers engage in streamlining internal processes and communications that deploy and deliver finished software as efficiently as possible. 
        This includes overseeing digital infrastructure, automating repetitive tasks, continuous improvement, and other responsibilities critical to high-level operations within the organization's development and IT departments.
    </template>
</category>

<category>
    <pattern>Programming</pattern>
    <template>
        Which of these sounds the most appealing to you?
    <button>
        Artificial intelligence and processing large volumes of data
    </button>
    <button>
        Building and optimizing the underlying logic and processes of a system
    </button>
    <button>
        Creating video games
    </button>
    </template>
</category>

<category>
    <pattern>Artificial intelligence and processing large volumes of data</pattern>
    <template>
        You may be interested in a career in artificial intelligence, machine learning, or data science. AI is a rapidly growing field with many overlapping closely related disciplines such as data science, data engineering, and machine learning. 
        Data science works with large data sets to build models for predictions and insights into an organization's processes and how they can be improved. 
        Data engineering is closely related to data science and creates pipelines that deliver accurate, clean data to data scientists for further processing. 
        Machine learning algorithms are used by many professionals in AI, data science, and related fields to build predictive models from a data set that isn't as easily analyzed by a human, unconvering correlations that might otherwise have gone unnoticed.
        AI curently includes many subdisciplines, such as image recognition, robotics, natural language processing, and swarm intelligence.
        It varies substantially by role and organization, but is primarily concerned with the development of automated processes and algorithms for machine intelligence to eventually surpass human capabilities.
    </template>
</category>

<category>
    <pattern>Building and optimizing the underlying logic and processes of a system</pattern>
    <template>
        You may be interested in careers in embedded systems and backend programming. Embedded systems are machines requiring computer-related functioning, which includes everyday consumer electronics as well as specialized hardware, such as medical devices and industrial machinery.
        Embedded systems have specialized requirements and constraints that can be challenging to work with and can create a very different environment that many other forms of software engineering intended for desktop computers and mobile devices.
        As the projects are generally rather specialized to a single device or limited family, creative yet difficult solutions can be utilized to optimize the machine's functioning, in contrast to most software engineering that must work on a wide array of devices and hardware.
        Backend programming works with databases, internal system architecture, security, and server-side application functioning.
        This includes all of the data flows and transactions that are invisible to the user, such as an order on a website being relayed to a database, payment processor, and other systems for processing before being shipped.
    </template>
</category>

<category>
    <pattern>Creating video games</pattern>
    <template>
        You may be interested in a career in game development. Game developers, as the name suggests, create video games, frequently using languages such as C++ and C#.
        Game development encompasses a number of roles and responsibilities, including the actual programming, artists, game designers, level designers, writers, audio engineers, and many others.
    </template>
</category>

<category>
    <pattern>bye</pattern>
    <template>I hope I've provided you with useful advice. Have a great day!</template>
</category>

<category>
    <pattern>thank you</pattern>
    <template>I hope I've provided you with useful advice. Have a great day!</template>
</category>

<category>
    <pattern>thanks</pattern>
    <template>I hope I've provided you with useful advice. Have a great day!</template>
</category>









</aiml>